Hello, everyone, and welcome back to another lesson here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的另一节课。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And my name is Catherine.
我是 Catherine。
And today, Marco, you and I are talking about movies, right?
今天，Marco，你我要聊聊电影，对吧？
We're talking a little bit about movies, but mostly we're having a big argument.
我们聊一点电影，但主要是要大吵一架。
Okay, I kind of like arguments.
好吧，我其实还挺喜欢吵架的。
Lots of great words and phrases for you to learn here in English.
有很多很棒的生词和短语等着你学。
But we've got an upper intermediate level lesson with some people who are not getting
我们有一节中高级课程，讲的是两个人相处得
along very well.
不太好。
It's a couple, a guy and a girl, and they're having a fight, as couples do.
是一对情侣，一男一女，他们在吵架，就像情侣常做的那样。
So we're going to be learning a lot of the different language that they are using in
所以我们会学到很多他们在
this very heated debate.
这场激烈争论中使用的不同语言。
So let's listen to this dialogue for the first time, and then we'll be right back.
我们先听一遍这段对话，然后马上回来。
Wow, that terrible movie is finally over.
哇，那部烂片终于结束了。
Next time I'm picking the film because I don't want to end up seeing a chick flick.
下次我来选电影，我可不想再看什么爱情片了。
Well, you should have picked.
那你刚才就该选啊。
In the end, you always complain about everything.
到头来，你总是抱怨个不停。
Not everything.
不是所有事。
Just this film.
就这部电影。
Even the title was ridiculous.
连片名都那么可笑。
And it's so long.
还那么长。
Those were the two and a half most wasted hours of my life.
那是我生命中最浪费的两个半小时。
So much so that I'm thinking about asking them to give me my money back.
我甚至想找他们退钱。
I'm thinking of taking you back home.
我想带你回家。
I thought we could have a nice evening, but you're always so negative.
我本来以为我们能有个愉快的晚上，但你总是这么消极。
I'm only complaining about a movie that I could have rented or bought and then thrown
我只是在抱怨一部我本来可以租来或买来然后扔进
in the garbage.
垃圾桶的电影。
You see, that's what I'm talking about.
你看，我说的就是这个。
I can't stand your sarcastic jokes anymore.
我再也受不了你的讽刺笑话了。
Next time, go with your gay friend who is more in touch with his feelings.
下次，跟你那个更懂感情的娘娘腔朋友去吧。
Well, he's more of a man than you are.
哼，他比你更有男人味。
At least he appreciates love stories.
至少他懂得欣赏爱情故事。
Love stories?
爱情故事？
More like one night stands.
更像是一夜情吧。
Don't criticize Mario, or else I'll start on those fat, drunk friends of yours.
别说 Mario，不然我就开始说你那些又胖又醉的朋友。
They're no saints.
他们可不是什么圣人。
My friends?
我朋友？
Fat?
胖？
What about those whales you call friends?
那你那些鲸鱼朋友呢？
You're unbearable.
你真让人受不了。
You can walk home.
你自己走回家吧。
I'm leaving.
我走了。
I think the guy was exaggerating a little bit.
我觉得那男的有点夸张了。
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
I think they were both exaggerating.
我觉得他们俩都夸张了。
You know, by the end of an argument, both people are saying things that maybe they don't
你知道，吵架到最后，两个人都会说一些可能不是
mean.
真心的气话。
I think we'll talk a little bit more about this towards the end of the show, but now,
我们会在节目结尾再聊这个，但现在，
why don't we take a look at language takeaway.
我们先来看看语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright on language takeaway today, we have four words and the first one that you probably
好的，今天的语言要点，我们有四个词，第一个你大概
saw in the very first sentence is a chick flick.
在第一句话里就看到了：chick flick。
Chick flick.
Chick flick。
So, first of all, the word chick means a woman.
首先，chick 这个词指女人。
It's slang and it's not very nice.
是俚语，不太礼貌。
It's not very nice.
不太礼貌。
No.
对。
Well, I mean, between guys, you would use it as like, oh, this chick or that chick,
嗯，我的意思是，男人之间会用，比如“这个 chick”或“那个 chick”，
but you wouldn't really walk up to a girl and call her a chick, right?
但你不会直接走到一个女孩面前叫她 chick，对吧？
No, you wouldn't say, hey, chick, what's up?
对，你不会说“嘿，chick，咋样？”
Not something you want to say.
这不是你想说的话。
So chick is a slang word for a girl or a woman and a chick flick is a girl's movie.
所以 chick 是女孩或女人的俚语，chick flick 就是女孩看的电影。
So a flick is a movie.
所以 flick 是电影。
Another slang word.
另一个俚语。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is the slang phrase for flick.
所以这是 flick 的俚语说法。
So hey, Marco, what flicks are showing at the movie theater?
所以，嘿，Marco，电影院在放什么 flicks？
All right.
好的。
Yeah.
嗯。
So movies.
就是电影。
So in the chick flick is usually a romantic movie, a drama, something that's very, um.
所以 chick flick 通常是指浪漫电影、剧情片，那种很……
Like beaches.
比如《海滩》。
Beaches is a chick flick.
《海滩》就是一部 chick flick。
I don't know if you've ever seen that.
不知道你看过没有。
I've never seen it.
我没看过。
So he's just not that into you is one of those new chick flicks.
所以《他其实没那么喜欢你》是那种新的 chick flick。
Or like how to lose a guy in 10 days.
或者像《十天丢个郎》。
Yeah.
嗯。
How to lose a guy in 10 days or the devil wears Prada.
《十天丢个郎》或《穿普拉达的女王》。
Bride Wars.
《新娘大作战》。
Wow.
哇。
Lots of chick flicks.
好多 chick flick。
I've actually never seen any one of these except how to lose a guy in 10 days.
其实这些我一部都没看过，除了《十天丢个郎》。
I've actually only seen that one.
我只看了那一部。
All right.
好的。
So chick flick is a girl's or woman's movie.
所以 chick flick 就是女孩或女人看的电影。
And next up we have a word, sarcastic.
下一个词是 sarcastic。
We're talking about sarcastic jokes.
我们说的是 sarcastic jokes。
So sarcastic jokes or somebody being sarcastic.
所以是讽刺的笑话，或者某人很 sarcastic。
God, Marco, you're always so sarcastic.
天哪，Marco，你总是这么 sarcastic。
So what would sarcasm sound like?
那讽刺听起来是什么样？
Um, yeah, he's really funny.
嗯，他真有趣。
All right.
好的。
So it's not really what you're saying.
所以关键不在于你说什么。
It's kind of how you're saying it.
而在于你怎么说。
Right.
对。
So it's kind of like by saying, he's really funny.
所以就像说“他真有趣”。
You're saying, yeah, he's a funny guy.
你是在说“嗯，他是个有趣的人”。
But if I say, oh, he's really funny.
但如果我说“哦，他真有趣”。
I'm saying he's not funny.
我其实是在说“他一点都不有趣”。
He's being mean or he's a jerk.
他刻薄或者是个混蛋。
Sarcasm is kind of one of those things that it's a little bit difficult to learn how to
讽刺是那种有点难学会
do or to actually get it right.
或掌握好的东西。
Especially in English.
尤其是在英语里。
Right?
对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
Marco, great explanation.
Marco，解释得真好。
Exactly.
没错。
That's the way it goes.
就是这样。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是啊。
You're so funny.
你真有趣。
So you're amazing.
你真了不起。
You should go to you.
你应该去……
You went to sarcasm school.
你上过讽刺学校吧。
So my parents like to say.
我爸妈常这么说。
You can be really mean, Catherine.
你可以很刻薄，Catherine。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Just kidding.
开玩笑的。
All right.
好的。
So apart from being sarcastic, you can criticize someone.
除了讽刺之外，你还可以批评别人。
Like you're ever critical.
说得好像你经常批评人似的。
All right.
好吧。
Sorry, I'll stop.
抱歉，我不说了。
You're really into character right now.
你现在真是入戏太深了。
All right.
好吧。
So critical to criticize someone is to complain about them or to say that the things that
所以，“批评”某人就是抱怨他们，或者说他们做的事情
they do are not very good.
不太好。
So you can criticize a person or a movie.
所以你可以批评一个人或一部电影。
Yeah.
是的。
So this movie wasn't very good.
所以这部电影不怎么样。
It wasn't funny.
它不好笑。
The actors were bad.
演员也很差。
It was really long.
它太长了。
These are criticisms.
这些都是批评。
Criticisms.
批评。
All right.
好吧。
Well, and then moving on, the girl was finally tired of the guy and his complaints.
嗯，接着往下，女孩终于受够了那个男人和他的抱怨。
And she said he's unbearable.
她说他让人受不了。
Gosh, you're unbearable.
天哪，你真让人受不了。
So the root of this word is to be able to like to stand something, to bear it.
所以这个词的词根是“能够忍受”或“承受”某事。
And so if you're unbearable, something is unbearable, you just can't stand it.
所以如果你让人受不了，或者某事让人受不了，就是你无法忍受。
All right.
好吧。
So you're tired of it.
所以你厌烦了。
You can't stand it.
你受不了了。
She thinks he's so unbearable, she makes him get out of the car.
她觉得他太让人受不了了，就让他下车。
And she leaves.
然后她走了。
Yeah.
是的。
She said you can walk home.
她说你可以走回家。
All right.
好吧。
So that's an unbearable person, right?
所以这就是一个让人受不了的人，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
So we took a look at those four main words here in our dialogue.
所以我们看了对话中的这四个主要词汇。
Let's move on now to some of the phrases that we found in Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看看“流利度构建”中的一些短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
This first one's a common one, especially when we talk about women and men and the relationship
第一个很常见，尤其是当我们谈论男女以及
between women and men.
男女之间的关系时。
We say about men that maybe they should be more in touch with their feelings or their
我们常说男人也许应该更关注自己的感受或
feminine side.
女性化的一面。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, so if you're saying to be more in touch with your feminine side, what exactly are
好的，所以如果你说“更关注你的女性化一面”，你到底在
you saying?
说什么？
It's a good question.
这是个好问题。
Well, what you're saying is that you want to be able to express your feelings more or
嗯，你的意思是希望自己能更多地表达感受，或者
you want to be able to understand more about your feminine side or something like this.
希望更了解自己的女性化一面之类的。
So to be in touch with is more about yourself.
所以“关注”更多是关于自己。
It's about self-reflection and self-understanding.
是关于自我反思和自我理解。
So you could say, I'm a very serious person, but I want to make some changes in my life.
所以你可以说，我是个很严肃的人，但我想在生活中做些改变。
So I'm trying to be more in touch with my inner child.
所以我试着更关注自己的童心。
Your inner child.
你的童心。
All right.
好吧。
So to be in touch with, and it's usually related to feelings, to something intangible.
所以“关注”通常与感受、无形的东西有关。
Or to behavior.
或者与行为有关。
To behavior.
与行为有关。
All right.
好吧。
Moving on now, a heated phrase, a one night stand.
接下来，一个热辣的短语：“一夜情”。
Oh, I'll let you explain this one, Marco.
哦，这个让马可来解释吧。
All right.
好吧。
So a one night stand is a casual and very quick temporal encounter that's usually a
所以“一夜情”是一种随意的、非常短暂的临时相遇，通常
sexual encounter.
是性方面的相遇。
It's romantic, right?
是浪漫的，对吧？
So it can be between two different people.
所以可以发生在两个人之间。
They meet each other one night.
他们某晚相遇。
They have a relationship for one night only, and then they never see each other again.
他们只维持一晚的关系，然后再也不见。
So it's casual.
所以很随意。
It's casual.
很随意。
Very good.
非常好。
So yeah, you would see this.
所以是的，你会看到这个。
You see this a lot in shows like, you know, Sex in the City and all that stuff.
你在像《欲望都市》之类的剧里经常看到。
Yeah, they have a lot of one night stands in that show.
是的，那部剧里有很多一夜情。
All right.
好吧。
So a one night stand.
所以“一夜情”。
And well, related to this, the girl was criticizing his friends, and she said, they're no saints.
嗯，与此相关，女孩在批评他的朋友，她说他们不是圣人。
Okay.
好的。
So we can say this in many different ways.
所以我们可以用很多不同的方式说这个。
He's no saint.
他不是圣人。
She's no saint.
她不是圣人。
Or I'm no saint.
或者我不是圣人。
You're no saint.
你不是圣人。
So a saint is a good person.
所以“圣人”是个好人。
It's a word that we use in religion to say someone who's like Mother Teresa, or someone
这是一个宗教用语，指像特蕾莎修女那样的人，或者
who's just really good and kind.
非常善良、仁慈的人。
Doesn't commit any sins.
不犯任何罪。
Exactly.
没错。
And so to say, I'm no saint is to say, well, I do bad things, or I say bad things.
所以说“我不是圣人”就是承认，嗯，我做坏事，或者说坏话。
I'm not perfect.
我不完美。
Okay.
好的。
So he or they, they're no saints.
所以他或他们，他们不是圣人。
They do bad stuff too.
他们也做坏事。
Yeah, very good.
是的，非常好。
So that's the way that you would use, he's no saint, they're no saints.
所以这就是你使用“他不是圣人”、“他们不是圣人”的方式。
All right.
好吧。
So I think now we should listen to our dialogue for the last time, and we'll be right back.
所以我想现在我们该最后一次听对话了，我们马上回来。
Wow, that terrible movie is finally over.
哇，那部烂片终于结束了。
Next time I'm picking the film because I don't want to end up seeing a chick flick.
下次我来选电影，因为我不想再看爱情片了。
Well, you should have picked.
嗯，你当时就该选。
In the end, you always complain about everything.
到头来，你总是抱怨一切。
Not everything, just this film.
不是一切，只是这部电影。
Even the title was ridiculous.
连片名都很荒谬。
And it's so long.
而且它太长了。
Those were the two and a half most wasted hours of my life.
那是我生命中最浪费的两个半小时。
So much so that I'm thinking about asking them to give me my money back.
以至于我在想让他们退我钱。
I'm thinking of taking you back home.
我在想把你送回家。
I thought we could have a nice evening, but you're always so negative.
我本以为我们能有个愉快的夜晚，但你总是这么消极。
I'm only complaining about a movie that I could have rented or bought and then thrown
我只是在抱怨一部我本可以租或买来然后扔进
in the garbage.
垃圾桶的电影。
You see, that's what I'm talking about.
你看，这就是我说的。
I can't stand your sarcastic jokes anymore.
我再也受不了你的讽刺笑话了。
Next time, go with your gay friend who's more in touch with his feelings.
下次，跟你那个更关注自己感受的同志朋友去吧。
Well, he's more of a man than you are.
嗯，他比你更像个男人。
At least he appreciates love stories.
至少他欣赏爱情故事。
Love stories?
爱情故事？
More like one night stands.
更像是“一夜情”。
Don't criticize Mario, or else I'll start on those fat drunk friends of yours.
别批评马里奥，否则我就开始说你那些胖醉鬼朋友了。
They're no saints.
他们也不是圣人。
My friends?
我的朋友？
Fat?
胖？
What about those whales you call friends?
那你那些叫“鲸鱼”的朋友呢？
You're unbearable.
你真让人受不了。
You can walk home.
你走回家吧。
I'm leaving.
我要走了。
Bye.
再见。
Good luck.
祝你好运。
Bye.
再见。
All right, so, Catherine, is this an argument that you would say is typical among couples?
好的，那么，凯瑟琳，你觉得这是情侣间典型的争吵吗？
Or maybe people that are probably about to break up?
还是说可能是快要分手的人之间才会有的？
Not couples that are happy, I would say.
我觉得不是幸福的情侣会有的。
But yeah, you definitely have people who are...
但确实，有些人会这样……
Well, I guess it's kind of the battle of the sexes, right?
嗯，我想这有点像两性之间的较量，对吧？
You have people who are different genders and so they don't always understand each other.
不同性别的人，所以不一定总能理解对方。
You know, you want to have your girlfriends as a girl and your girlfriends behave and
你知道，作为女生，你想和闺蜜在一起，而闺蜜们会以某种方式相处和
talk in a certain way together and guys do the same thing but with their friends.
聊天，男生们也一样，但和他们的朋友在一起时。
And so sometimes you have these clashes, these interactions that are negative and you know
所以有时候会有这些冲突，这些负面的互动，而且你知道
when people are upset with each other, they say mean things.
当人们彼此生气时，他们会说刻薄的话。
And especially I think in this case, they don't really like each other's friends.
特别是这次，我觉得他们真的不喜欢对方的朋友。
Exactly.
没错。
And that's a kind of a common thing.
这还挺常见的。
Like a guy doesn't like his girlfriend's friends because maybe they gossip too much or something
比如，男生不喜欢女朋友的朋友，可能是因为她们太爱八卦或什么的。
like that.
类似这样。
And the same thing with the girls, right?
女生也一样，对吧？
Because a guy's friends maybe drink too much.
因为男生的朋友可能喝太多酒了。
Drink too much, play too many card games.
喝太多酒，玩太多牌。
They're single.
他们都是单身。
So I think a lot of times these problems also have to do with the fact that like when a
所以我觉得很多时候这些问题也跟这个事实有关：当一个
girl is with her girlfriend, she maybe acts differently.
女生和她的闺蜜在一起时，她可能表现得不一样。
Or when a guy is with his guy friends.
或者当一个男生和他的哥们在一起时。
And so that's weird sometimes for the relationship because you see your partner acting differently
所以这对关系来说有时很奇怪，因为你看到你的伴侣和别人在一起时表现不同。
with other people.
和别人在一起时。
Right.
对。
So, do you like your boyfriend or girlfriend's friends?
那么，你喜欢你男朋友或女朋友的朋友吗？
Do you get in fights about this kind of stuff?
你们会为这种事吵架吗？
Or you know what?
或者你知道吗？
The in-laws.
还有姻亲。
Oh, that's a whole another situation.
哦，那完全是另一回事了。
That's a whole another situation.
那完全是另一回事了。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
Alright, so we want to hear from you and also if you have any questions or comment suggestions,
好了，所以我们想听听你的意见，如果你有任何问题或评论建议，
come to EnglishPod.com and you can leave it on our lessons page or you can email us at
请访问EnglishPod.com，你可以留在我们的课程页面上，或者发邮件到
EnglishPod at PraxisLanguage.com.
EnglishPod@PraxisLanguage.com。
We hope to see you on the website in the near future.
我们希望在不久的将来在网站上见到你。
Please get in touch with us.
请与我们联系。
That's all for today.
今天就到这里。
So bye-bye.
那么，再见。
Bye-bye.
再见。